quia.com 2001-06-03

# Quia - Privacy Policy

* * *

Quia Corporation is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of all of Quia Corporation's offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. The following explains the information we gather and how we gather it, and our policies with respect to its use. **Our Commitment To Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage.

This policy will let you know the following:

  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you
  * What cookies are and how they are used
  * How your information is used
  * Who is collecting your information
  * With whom your information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information
  * How you can access, update, or delete your information
  * What kind of security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information
  * How Quia Corporation protects children's privacy
  * What else you should know about your online privacy
  * Additional information

* * *

What personally identifiable information does Quia Corporation collect from me?  
Quia Corporation collects information in several ways from different parts of our Web site.

Some personal information is gathered when you register. Quia Corporation asks for your name, e-mail address, username, and password during registration. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Quia Corporation and are able to take full advantage of Quia's free service.

In addition to during registration, we may ask you for personal information at other times, such as when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. Quia Corporation also encourages users to complete surveys that we use for site enhancement and research purposes. If you contact Quia Corporation, such as through the use of surveys, we may keep a record of that correspondence. Wherever Quia Corporation collects personal information, we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

Top

* * *

What are cookies and how does Quia Corporation use them?  
As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Quia Corporation uses  cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All sites on Quia Corporation where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies.

Generally, we use cookies to: 

(1) Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "Log In" and is modified when you "Log Out" of our services. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Quia Corporation services, such as the activity and quiz creation tools, that require registration in order to participate.

(2) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Quia Corporation is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior.

(3) Identify registered users who take our [online survey](http://www.quia.com/survey.html).

(4) Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Quia Corporation's Web sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Quia Corporation a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Quia Corporation may also use their own cookies.

Quia Corporation also collects [ IP addresses](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/TERM/I/IP_address.html) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers.

Top

* * *

How does Quia Corporation use my information?  
Quia Corporation's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our sites. This includes personalization services, interactive communications, and many other types of services, all of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Quia Corporation is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, Quia Corporation plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, instructors of a particular subject). Quia Corporation takes the advertisement and displays it to users meeting those criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only Quia Corporation has access to individuals' accounts. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads through Quia Corporation Web locations. Also with this type of targeting, the advertisements are more likely to be of particular interest to Quia users. 

Quia Corporation does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, from our server log files, or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Quia Corporation may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners.

Top

* * *

Who is collecting information?  
When you are on a Quia Corporation site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Quia Corporation alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Quia Corporation, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.

Please be aware that Quia Corporation Internet access partners, advertisers, and Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those Internet access partners, advertisers, and Web sites linked to Quia Corporation are not covered by this privacy statement.

Top

* * *

With whom does Quia Corporation share my information?  
As a general rule, Quia Corporation will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. _Business Partners & Sponsors_. Quia Corporation will never disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, unless it is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. _Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate_. Under confidentiality agreements, Quia Corporation may match user information with third party data. Also, Quia Corporation discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to current and prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. _Other_. Quia Corporation may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Quia Corporation's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Quia Corporation's rights or property, other Quia Corporation users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Quia Corporation may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

Top

* * *

What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?  
Quia Corporation may, from time to time, send you e-mail regarding our products and services. In addition, we may occasionally send you direct mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only Quia Corporation (or agents working on behalf of Quia Corporation and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. Quia will only send direct marketing mailings that allow you to unsubscribe (opt out) from the mailing list.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Quia Corporation services, such as the activity and quiz creation tools, that require registration in order to participate.

Quia Corporation does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain activities. 

Top

* * *

What is Quia Corporation's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?  
You may edit your Quia account information at any time by going to  http://www.quia.com/profileform.cgi. If you have forgotten your password, go to the Password Request Form. A new password will be automatically sent to the e-mail address you specified during registration. For all other problems signing in to Quia Corporation, please contact  Quia Support.

Please contact Quia Support for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your Quia Corporation account. Residual information will remain within our archive records.

If you are participating in a Quia Corporation promotion and you wish to update your e-mail address on the promotions mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related e-mail, please contact  Quia Support. 

Top

* * *

What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?  
Your Quia Corporation account information and Quia Corporation profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your Quia account information at any time by going to  http://www.quia.com/profileform.cgi. If you have forgotten your password, go to the Password Request Form. A new password will be automatically sent to the e-mail address you specified during registration. For all other problems signing in to Quia Corporation, please contact  Quia Support.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Quia Corporation will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. Also remember to log out of Quia before closing your browser. You can log out of Quia by clicking on the log out link available on most Web pages, or by going to  http://www.quia.com/logout.cgi. After logging out, make sure to close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

As a global company, Quia Corporation has international users all over the world. When you give Quia Corporation personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored, and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever Quia Corporation handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, Quia Corporation takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Quia Corporation cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

Top

* * *

What about children's privacy?  
Under the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, no Web site operator is permitted to require a child under the age of 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. Quia Corporation abides by this requirement. Quia Corporation does not gather information on the ages of our users and will never knowingly share personally identifying information about users who are under the age of 13 with business partners or other third parties. When contacting our users, Quia Corporation requests that anyone under the age of 13 forward the e-mail to a parent or guardian. All Quia account holders, including parents and children with Quia accounts, are subject to this Privacy Policy.

Top

* * *

What else should I know about my privacy?  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

When creating materials on the Quia Web site, you must choose whether or not to show your name and e-mail address. If you decide to show your name and e-mail address, you are making it available to others over the Internet. Furthermore, if you have chosen to have your name displayed on your Quia activity page(s) and you nominate an activity for it to appear on the Quia Directory, your name will appear in the directory. Remember that the choice of displaying your name and e-mail address on the Quia Web site is entirely up to you. By publishing your name and e-mail address, you may receive correspondence from other Quia users. For example, someone may send you an e-mail to let you know that your activity is extremely helpful, or to point out errors in your activity. Many Quia users appreciate the opportunity to receive this feedback; however, the choice to include this information is yours.

Additionally, Quia offers a home-page building tool, specifically designed to allow educators to custom build class pages for their own use. Just like any other home page building tool, the home pages created can be accessed by anyone over the Internet. Please do not include any information on your home page that you do not want to disclose over the Internet.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

Top

* * *

Additional Information  
If you have a question regarding this statement, or if a question was not addressed in this privacy policy, you may contact us at  Quia Support.. We will do our best to answer your question promptly and accurately.

Top

* * *

Also see...

  * [Electronic Frontier Foundation](http://www.eff.org/) \- a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online.
  * [Electronic Privacy Information Center](http://epic.org/)\- established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure.
  * [Privacy Issues Page](http://www.cdt.org/privacy) \- from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT).
  * [How to Protect Your Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission for consumers. 
  * [Kidz Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission about kids' privacy and the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

Top
